Henry C. Carpenter Letters, 1862-1864
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Henry C. Carpenter Letters, 1862-1864
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1996-008
1 folder; 0.1 cu. ft.
The papers consist of Carpenter's letters written between February 1862 and June 1864 while encamped in parts of Virginia and West Virginia.
Henry C. Carpenter
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Henry C. Carpenter Letters were donated to Special Collections in May 1996.
Biographical Information
Henry C. Carpenter was born in Bland County, Virginia. He served as a Corporal in Company H, 45th Virginia Infantry, during the Civil War. He participated in the Battle of Cloyd's Farm in May 1864, and died on October 6, 1864, in Woodstock, Virginia.
Scope and Content
The papers consist of letters from Carpenter to his sister Elizabeth, written between February 1862 and June 1864 while encamped in the Kanawha Valley of West Virginia; Monroe County, West Virginia; Saltville, Virginia; and Harrisonburg, Virginia. Also includes one letter to Elizabeth from Newton Thompson, written from Alderson's Ferry, Virginia, on June 4, 1863.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Civil War; Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865
Contents List
- Letters, 1862-1864 (Folder 1)
  - February 10, 1862
  - August 25, 1862
  - September 5, 1862
  - September 26, 1862
  - November 22, 1862
  - December 12, 1862
  - March 19, 1863
  - March 30, 1863
  - June 4, 1863
  - June 8, 1863
  - June 21, 1863
  - July 7, 1863
  - September 4, 1863
  - November 16, 1863
  - December 6, 1863
  - January 22, 1864
  - Febraury 11, 1864
  - April 21, 1864
  - May 20, 1864
  - June 2, 1864
  - June 4, 1864
  - June 22, 1864
  - July 29, 1864
  - October 12, 1864